Hello, I am the owner who lives with my Jindo dog, Hongsi. Today, I will share how my Hongsi and our neighbors can be happy together.
My Hongsi is a beautiful female Jindo dog, black-furred with sparse white patches scattered throughout.
When Hongsi was hurt fighting a badger on a mountain trail recently, I held her all night crying and nursing her. That night, we truly became family.
Yet when a neighbor flinches and steps back upon seeing Hongsi in the elevator, a corner of my heart aches.
I cannot blame them. To someone bitten by a dog before, a large dog can feel like pure fear itself.
Moreover, irresponsible owners who unleash their dogs or leave waste behind deepen the conflict even further.
So, for Hongsi and for our neighbors, I made up my mind to become a responsible guardian.
In Germany, a dog tax called Hundesteuer is collected and reinvested into clean parks and waste-bag stations.
The tax is not a burden but a warm promise, society sharing the responsibility of living alongside dogs.
In Japan, separate dog-run areas and walking zones are designated so dogs have their own space to play.
Within the designated areas Hongsi runs freely, while outside them neighbors can pass by at ease.
In one apartment, an elevator now has a button that signals a dog is on board.
Pressing it lets waiting neighbors know in advance, greatly reducing surprises and unwanted encounters.
In our neighborhood, owners gathered and started a community training group for dog socialization.
Hongsi learned to sit and wait, while I grew together with other owners by sharing know-how.
Now, in the elevator, I hold the leash short within two meters and keep Hongsi close beside my leg.
On days she is shy around people, I tie a yellow ribbon to signal that we need some distance today.
Neighbors, too, show respect, not touching or shouting without consent, and taking a step back.
Always carrying waste bags and cleaning up every trace, these small habits build everyone's trust.
As care builds little by little, people and Hongsi alike become safe, warm neighbors. Please love my Hongsi.