Hello everyone! Today, we will explore the birth secrets of Hangeul, the most scientific script in the world, and the principles of its vowels. How was Hangeul created?
Long ago, Koreans did not have their own script, so they wrote using borrowed Chinese characters. However, Hanja was so complex that only the noble class could use it, leaving commoners unable to read or write.
Seeing his people suffer from unfairness due to their inability to read the laws, King Sejong the Great felt deep sorrow. 'Pitying this, I newly create twenty-eight letters...'
Finally, in 1443, Hunminjeongeum, an innovative script that anyone could easily learn, was created. A wise person could learn it in a single morning, and even a less clever person within ten days.
Hangeul vowels were modeled after the three prime elements of the universe: Heaven, Earth, and Human. This system is known as 'Cheon-Ji-In'.
When the Heaven dot is attached to the right of the Human line, it becomes the bright vowel 'ㅏ', representing the rising sun in the east. If attached to the left, it becomes the dark vowel 'ㅓ', representing the setting sun in the west.
Similarly, if the Heaven dot is placed above the Earth line, it becomes the bright vowel 'ㅗ', representing the sun rising above the ground. If placed below, it becomes the dark vowel 'ㅜ', representing the sun sinking below the earth.
This systematic grouping where bright vowels (ㅏ, ㅗ) cluster together and dark vowels (ㅓ, ㅜ) cluster together creates Vowel Harmony, establishing a beautiful order in Korean grammar.
Now, let's learn how to pronounce simple vowels, which are often the trickiest for foreigners. Unlike English vowels, Korean monophthongs require keeping your mouth shape perfectly stable during pronunciation.
Here are the most confusing pair: 'ㅓ' and 'ㅗ'. For 'ㅓ', drop your jaw vertically to open wide while keeping your lips flat. In contrast, for 'ㅗ', you must round your lips tightly, as if holding a straw.
Next are 'ㅜ' and 'ㅡ'. For 'ㅜ', purse your lips tightly and push them forward. For 'ㅡ', stretch your lips flat horizontally into a forced smile, keeping your teeth close together.
Check yourself in the mirror! Your lips should round only when pronouncing 'ㅗ' and 'ㅜ'. When pronouncing 'ㅓ' and 'ㅡ', your lips must remain completely flat.
Practice these simple vowels in the mirror every day. Hit subscribe and like for more fun Korean learning! See you next time!
image: Flat 2D illustration in minimalist line art style showing an empty template screen for recommended video playlist frames, solid flat light beige background (#F5F5F0), whiteboard marker sketch texture, no watermark, no signatures.